Uzys SMI Merge Tool http://uzys.net
Uzys 통합 자막 생성기 http://uzys.net
내 이름은
올리버 퀸
My name is Oliver Queen.
지난 5년을
지옥에서 살고
After five years in hell,
한 가지 목표로
집에 돌아왔다
I have come home
with only one goal--
내 도시를
구하는 것
to save my city.
다른 사람들은
내 십자군에 합류했다
Now others have
joined my crusade.
스탈링 시티에 남은
사람들에게 난 올리버 퀸이다
To them, I am Oliver Queen.
But to the rest
of Starling City,
다른 사람이
되어야 한다
I am someone else.
다른 무엇이
되어야 한다
I am something else.
애로우
지난 이야기
Previously, on "Arrow"...
Man: Hello, Sara.
여긴 왜 왔어?
What are you doing here?
누가 이런 짓을 했건
꼭 찾아 낼꺼야
Oliver: Whoever did this,
I'm going to find them.
회사인수를 원하는
경쟁상대가 있습니다
Apparently there's
another bidder for the company.
누구요?
Who?
레이 팔머
Ray Palmer.
내가 이제 너의 보스야
Yes, I am your boss now.
안돼!
No! [Sobbing]
로이 난 널 믿지않아
그 누구도 믿지 않을꺼야
Thea: Roy, I don't
trust you, or anyone.
날 찾으려고 하지마
난 절대로 돌아오지 않을꺼야
Don't try to find me.
I am never coming back.
테아를 찾으러 가야겠어
Now I've got
to go get Thea.
오랜 시간이 지났는데
테아가 집에 오지않아
It's long past time
she came home.
잘했다
Well done.
고마워요
아빠
Thanks, Dad.
[Engine starts]
이제 우린 어디로 가요?
So, where are we going?
네가 원하는 곳
Wherever you want.
- 내가 원하는 곳이요?
- 왜 아니겠니?
It's up to me?
Why not?
난 여행을 많이 했어
I'm a well-traveled man.
난 세상을 곳곳을 다갔어
I've been every place
in the world there is.
그러나 당신은 여기서
나가고 싶겠네요
But you want
to get out of here.
왜냐하면 경찰이 당신이
살아있는것을 알면 찾아올테니까요
Because if the police know
you're alive, they come after you.
애로우도요
The Arrow, too.
넌 아주 통찰력이
있구나 테아
You're very
perceptive, Thea.
어떤사람들은 무언가를
그들이 미소뒤에 숨겨
Knowing when people are hiding
something behind their smiles.
네 엄마는 재능이 있었다
Your mother
had that talent.
그래
Yes.
만약에 누군가
내가 어디있는지 안다면
If someone knew
where I was,
유감스럽길 바란다
it would be
unfortunate--
우리둘을 위해서
for both of us.
그래서 왜 날 찾은거니?
So why did you
reach out to me?
당신이 찾았잖아요
You reached first.
그래
Still.
난 다시는
고통 받기 싫어요
I don't want to feel
this pain again.
다시는 상처받지
않고 싶어요
I don't want to hurt
아니면 다치는 것도 싫어요
or get hurt
평생 상처
받기 싫어요
ever again.
그리고 당신은
날 가르칠 사람으로 보이네요
And you seem like someone
who can teach me how not to.
[Horns honking]
[Tires squealing,
horns honking]
[Grunts]
내가 안 그랬어요
I didn't do it!
지난주에 어떤 여자가
건물 옥상에서 살해됐다
A woman was killed
on a rooftop last week.
검은 가죽옷, 금발, 마스크를 썻다
Black leather,
blonde hair, wore a mask!
- 내가 안죽였어요
- 너도 있었잖아!
I didn't kill her.
You were there!
난 그 일에
대해서 하나도 몰라요
I don't know
anything about it!
이 물건에서
너의 지문이 발견됐어
Your fingerprints
are on this.
술을 마시고 옥상에 올라갔어요
From a fifth I drank
up there, but I--
네가 본게 무엇이지?
What did you see?
아무것도
못봣어요
Nothing!
옥상에서 일어나니
시신들이 있었어요
I was up on the roof
with some buddies.
여자가 나타났어요
This lady,
she showed up
그 여자는 우리보고
가라고했어요
and she--
she told us to go!
보니까 그녀는 자신이
다룰줄아는 것 같았어요
Looked like she could handle
herself, you know?
당신이 누구찾는지 몰라도
Whoever it is
you're looking for,
그사람이 남자였으면
좋겠어요
I wouldn't want
to be him.
또 하나의 막다른 길이야
Another dead end.
그게 저한테 일주일을
프린트하는데 뻈었어요
It took me a week to get
a hit off that print.
난 일부분을 복원한
것을 가지고있어요
I had to reconstruct
the partial
자동완성이되는 인덱싱
알고리즘을 이용해서요
using a predictive
indexing algorithm.
적당한 시기에
그의 집게손가락이 있었어요
Appropriate, since it was
his index finger...
지금 그렇게 특별히
관련있지는 않네요
Not particularly
relevant now.
걱정마 우리가 찾을꺼야
그는 어딘가에 있어
Don't worry, Oliver, we'll find him.
He's out there somewhere.
아니, 그렇지않아
No, he's not.
트레일이 차가워졌어
Trail's gone cold.
난 이일을하는게 싫어요
I hate to do this, but I have to
head off to work.
테크 빌리지 일찍열어요?
Tech Village
is open this early?
정확하지 않을꺼야
Not exactly.
테아가 이탈리아 어디서
머무르는지 생각안했어요?
Have you figured out
where in Italy Thea's staying?
네 그거말인데..
테아는 이탈리아에 없어요
Yeah, about that--
she's not in Italy.
Hmm?
아니면 유럽이던가
테아는...
Or Europe.
Or, well, she's--
테아는 어딨어요?
Where is she?
테아의 전화기로
찾아냈어요
I had to ping her cell phone
to find out
이탈리아에서 메세지 보낸것이
where in Italy she
was texting from.
코르토 말테즈로 바뀌었어요
Turns out, came back
Corto Maltese.
코르토 말테즈는 섬이에요
남아메리카에 위치했어요
Corto's an island
off of South America.
너의가족과, 섬이 무슨관계이야?
What's up with your family
and islands?
잠깐만요 올리버
Wait, Oliver.
테아의 편지에는
절대로 자기를 찾지말래요
Thea's letter said
not to come find her.
그 편지는 네한테
간거지 나한테 온게아니야
That letter was addressed
to you, not to me.
난 로럴을 보면서 새라도 잃었어
I'm watching Laurel
go through losing Sara.
내 동생이 집으로
와야할 시간이야
It's time for my sister
to come home.
머하는 거야?
What are you doing?
테아는 나때문에
떠났어요
Thea's gone because of me.
왜냐하면 내가 그녀한테
했던 거짓말때문에요
Because the lies
that I told her.
그래서 난 당신과같이
이걸 바로잡을거에요
So I owe this to both
of you to make things right.
그게아니라..
머하는거야?
No. What are
you...doing?
그 활들고
여행할수는 없잖아
You can't travel
with that.
난 솔직히 비행기
한번도 안봤어요
I've actually never
been on a plane before.
[Babbling]
아무것도 안해야지
I know. You're not
doing anything
내가 널 그대로
평생 보지
and I could literally
watch you forever.
그래?
Oh, yeah?
한번은 그 애가
남자를 발견하겠어?
What about once
she discovers boys?
글쎄 내 글록(glock) 아기
Well, that's what my Glock
is for, right, baby?
맞아 걔는 내 글록이야
Right. It's my Glock.
난 다음 몇 일동안 애기하고
몇가지 좋은 시간을 즐길거야
I'm going to enjoy some quality time
with her for the next few days.
난 귀저기 가는것을
기대하고있어
I'm even looking forward
to changing a few diapers.
그리고 난 좋은 결과를
보면 믿을거야
And I'm looking forward to believing
that when I see it.
왜 쉬고 있어?
Why the time off?
다시 팀을 나가게?
You quit
the team again?
아니, 올리버가
코르토 말테즈에간대
No, Oliver's going
to Corto Maltese
몇 칠 동안
for a couple of days.
올리버하고 같이가고 싶어?
Could you
go with him?
난 아직 올리버하고 시간을
보낼 준비가 안됐다는 말이야?
Like I don't already spend
enough time with Oliver as it is?
팀 애로우가 스탈링시티에
가르릉 거리는 고양이같아
Team Arrow may have Starling City
purring like a kitten,
남은 세상은 여전히
위험한 곳이야
but the rest of the world is still
a very dangerous place.
코르토 말테즈를 포함해서
Including Corto Maltese.
라일라 나 주소적혀있는거 싫어하잖아
Lyla, I already don't like
where this is headed.
들판 정보원을 보낼꺼야
We have a field operative
down there who's gone dark.
알았어, 그래서 군대
요원을 보낸다고?
All right, so send an agent.
Send a task force.
그는 아무 문제도
일으키지 않을꺼야
He's not in any
kind of trouble.
그는 그의 패닉
버튼을 누르지않아
He hasn't touched
his panic button.
그는 아마도 미인의 별장에서
술마시고 있을꺼야
He's probably just drunk
in some belleza's villa.
마크는 몇 일을 시간에서 시간으로 보내
Mark Shaw's been known
to miss a few days from time to time.
[Exhales]
그냥 내일에 찬성해주면 안되?
Will you just
do me a favor...
그리고 만약에 그가 괜찮을까?
And see if he's ok?
그한테 확인하라고 할께
Tell him to check in.
이틀뒤 난 정찰하러가
Two more days and I'm going to have
to call in the cavalry.
난 그를 월러하고
문제를일으키게하고싶지않아
And I don't want to get him into
trouble with Waller.
마크는 오랜 친구잖아
Mark's an old friend.
그녀는 내가 떠나고
흥미로운것들을 하지않을꺼야
She better not do anything interesting
while I'm gone.
다음엔 네 손을 올려
Next time,
keep your hands up.
[Velcro tearing]
테드 그랜트?
Ted Grant?
글쎄 배지가 뜻하는것은
넌 여기 없다는 거네
Well, I guess that badge means
you're not here
자기 방어 수업
for a self defense
class.
아니, 난 이미 정당한 몫을 했어
No, I've already had
my fair share.
난 당신 학생 때문에
왔어요 톰 브론슨
I'm here about one
of your students, Tom Bronson.
현장의 목격자거든요
A witness places him
at the scene
어젯밤에 건물에 침입한 사건에서요
of a break-in last night.
글쎄 그건 불가능해
Well, that's not possible.
톰과 나는 어젯밤에 스파링에 있었거든
See, because Tom and I
were sparring last night.
그래트씨 변호사한테한
거짓말은
Mr. Grant, do you
know that lying
to the district
attorney
법에 위반되는걸 아세요?
is against the law?
그말은 내가 거짓말을 한다는건가?
If by that, you mean
am I willing to lie
착한 아이가 실수를 한것에
대해 덮어서 빠져나오게해주려고?
in order to keep a good kid who
just happened to make a stupid mistake
내 생각에는 너도 내대답을 알텐데?
out of this system?
I think you know my answer.
당신은 위증죄를 한게
결백하다고 생각해요?
Are you admitting
to perjury, Mr. Grant?
이제 그건 큰 단어군
Now that's a big word.
난 그냥 멍청한 파이터야
I'm just a dumb fighter.
안 그래?
Right?
이봐 톰은 어제 나랑
여기 있었어
Look, Tom was here
with me last night.
우리는 어퍼컷
콤비네이션을 연습했어
We worked on his
uppercut combinations.
말 했다시피 이도시에는
선량한 사람들이 많아
Like I said, in this city,
there's a lot of good people
누가 안좋은
손에 거래하는것을 찾았내
who get dealt bad hands.
그들은 누구를 잃을때
자기를 잃는거야
They lose someone, they lose themselves,
which is why they
여기와서 분노를 풀어
come in here
to work off that rage.
난 타입에 없는 사람을 골랐어
I've gotten good
at picking out the types.
너 같은 타입
Types just like you.
내가 화가나있다면
그건 내가 거래를 해서에요
If I'm angry,
it's because I'm dealing
누군가 지방검사한테
거짓말을해
with someone who's
willing to lie to a D.A.
불량배를 보호하려고 해서에요
to protect a punk kid.
난 이게 사건이라고 생각되지않네요
I don't think
that's the case.
어느 쪽이든
Either way,
여기와서 무엇을 하고싶으면
일 다끝내고 와
if you do have something
you want to work off...
테아와 누가 먼저 얘기할까요?
So what's the play
with Thea?
내가 그녀하고 먼저 혼자서 얘기해야할까?
Do you mind if I talk
to her alone first?
정말 오랜만이지
It's been a while.
펠리시티가 어딨는지 알려줬어?
Felicity able
to pin her down?
펠리시티가 주소를 줬어
She gave me an address.
테아!
Thea!
Señor.
Cómo puedo ayudarlo?
Estoy buscando
a mi hermana.
당신은 미아의 오빠겠군요
You must be Mia's brother.
미아와 닮은것을 봤어요
I see the resemblance.
미아가 근처에있나요?
Is "Mia" around?
그녀는 카페에서 일하고 있어요
She works. At the cafe.
카페가 어디에요?
Where's the cafe?
- 보여드릴께요
- 감사합니다
I'll show you.
Thank you.
[Exhales]
난 남아메리카로 오지
않았는데요
I didn't come all the way
to South America
난 중독시켰군요?
to have you poison me, did I?
[Laughs]
이건 명상적인 차란다
It's a meditative tea.
이게 네정신과 몸을
활성화시켜줄꺼야
It will activate
your mind and body.
내 생각에는 조금맞는게
차보다 더필요할거같네요
I think I'm going to need
a little bit more than tea
to learn how
to use one of those.
sohei 전사들은 싸울때 정신을
The Sohei Buddhist
warriors believed that
first you fight
with the mind...
검보다 더믿었어
then your sword.
난 내가 전사가 되기위해
훈련 받던게 기억이 난다
I remember when
I was training
to be a warrior.
난 너처럼
I began
just like you--
내 아내의 죽음에
대해 충격을 받았어
devastated
by my wife's death.
난... 화가 났었지
I was...angry,
그리고 상처 받았어
and hurt.
고통은 참을 수 없었지
The pain
was unbearable.
이것처럼
Like this.
미쳤군요!
손 치워요!
You're out of your mind!
Put your hand in here!
모든 전사들은 간단한
믿음을 배워야 한다
Every warrior must learn
the simple truth--
고통은 필연적이야
that pain
is inevitable,
그리고 고통은 선택이지
and suffering
is optional.
[Gasping]
제발 그러지마요..
Please, don't--
내가 생각하는 그것을 하지마요
Don't do what I think
you're going to do!
넌 나보고 가르쳐 달라고 했어
You asked me
to teach you.
안돼
No.
♪ Arrow 3x03 ♪
Corto Maltese
Original Air Date on October 22, 2014
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
오역 의역 있음 그래도 잘보셈^^
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
Aquí tienes.
테아
Thea.
좋아보이네
Good to see you.
오빠도 좋아보여
You, too.
어어어떻게?
How--how did you--
글쎄 정확히 아말피
코스트가 아니잖아
Well, it's not exactly
the Amalfi Coast.
[Sighs]
Voy a cerrar, earnesto.
너 스페인 시험에서
떨어지지 않았어?
Didn't you flunk
Spanish?
완전히 건너뛴건 아니니까
More like
skipped it altogether.
너 좋아보인다
Well, you look good.
너 머리 자른거
마음에드네
I like
your hair cut.
고마워 머리 짧게 자르고 싶었어
Thank you. Yeah,
wanted it short, you know.
여기는 더워서 말이지
It gets hot down here.
거짓말해서 미안해
I'm sorry I lied to you
올리
about it, Ollie.
난 그냥 시간이
필요했어
I just needed some space.
괜찮아 넌 5개월동안
시간을 가졌잖아
It's ok. You've had
five months of it.
그냥 방문이 아니구나
This isn't just a visit.
네것도 가져왔어
Got one
for you, too.
엄마 일이 있고 난뒤
After mom,
난 왜 네가
스탈링을 떠났는지 이해했어
I understood why
you left Starling.
하지만 테아
But Thea,
난 네가 그리워
I miss you.
그리고 난 네가
집으로 돌아왔으면해
And I would really like it
if you came home.
나도 그리워해
I miss you, too.
그리고 엄청 사랑해
And I love you...so much.
하지만 난 스탈링 시티로
돌아가지 않을꺼야
But I'm never coming back
to Starling City.
[Thea gasping]
Ahh!
전 못해요 죄송해요
I can't. Sorry.
너한텐 힘이 있다
테아
There is strength
in you, Thea.
네 자신을 보지못하는것을 난 봤다
I see it, even if you can't
see it yourself.
죄송해요
I'm sorry, this--
이건 제가 아니에요
난 당신이아니에요 전 못해요!
this just isn't me.
I'm not like you. I can't do this!
괜찮다
It's all right.
그건 네 잘못이 아니다
It's not your fault.
내 잘못이지
It's mine.
퀸회사 주식이 10달러가 올랐어요
Q.C. stock up 10 bucks
at the open.
사랑스럽군!
That is love, ha!
미스 스모크 좋은 아침
Ah, miss Smoak,
good morning--
내 생각에는 난 여기서
밤새도록 있었어
I think. I've been
here all night.
내 프로듀서가 남긴 것들 그런것들말이야
My predecessor left
things a little, um,
예의바른 길이네 이것도말해야해? 약간 불안정하네
what's the polite way
to say this? Little wonky.
미안해 내가 횡설수설했네
카페인이 살짝 많아
Sorry if I'm rambling.
I'm a little over-caffeinated.
난 그냥 에스프레소
세컵을 가지고있어
I just had
three espressos.
내가 멈추게 거기 가많이 있어!
Speaking of coffee--
Let me stop you right there!
내 자신한테 말한거에요
난 회사가 일어섰으면 좋겠어요
I told myself
that I would stand firm
몇 가지 점 말이에요
on a few points.
어제밤 이메일은 늦지않았네
개인적인 심부름은아니야
No late night emails,
no personal errands,
그리고 절대로 커피는 안먹었어요
and definitely no coffee.
에스프레소 사주지마요
There'll be no espressos
brought to you by me.
난 단단한 것에 일어섯어요
라스토 포인트말이에요
I stand very firm
on that last point.
그리고 당신의 신념을 존경해
And I admire
your conviction.
제리 콘웨이, 너의 비서야
This is Jerry Conway,
your executive assistant.
그리고 난 커피를 얻기 위해 그를 좋아하는지 알고 싶었어
And I wanted to know
if you'd like him to get you a coffee.
아니면 넌 그냥 일반적으로 안티라떼야?
Or are you just
anti-latte in general?
음... 행정 도우미?
Um...Executive assistant?
내 생각에는 라떼에 예스인것같아
I think that's
a yes on the latte.
고마워 제리
Thank you, Jerry.
우리 일하러 가야 하는건가? 좋아
Should we get to
work? Excellent.
응용 과학
Applied Sciences.
퀸회사 첨단 연구 부문
Q.C.'s bleeding edge
research division,
어떤 미친 사람을
작년에 폭발로 날렸어
till some wacko
blew it up last year.
난 그들이 이유를 가지고
있는것을 확신해
I'm sure they had
their reasons.
요점은 내 계획의 초석이라는 것
The point is, it's the cornerstone
for my plan
퀸회사를 다시 짓고
to rebuild
Queen Consolidated
난 내사람을 가졌다
and thus the city.
I've had my people
밤과 낮에 일하면서
구출이 그들이 할수있는것이야
working day and night
salvaging what they can,
파일 서버도 포함해서
including this--
a file server
응용과학 디자인 작업을 말이지
containing Applied
Science's design work.
불행하게 이건 일이아니야
It's not working,
unfortunately,
계좌에 대규모 폭발이 일어나지
on account of being caught
in a massive explosion.
내가 데이터에 액세스
해주기를 원하는거죠
You want me to access the data.
뛰어난 생각은
일할 준비를 해주지
A brilliant mind
at work already.
난 일하러 돌아가야해
Speaking of, I got
to get back to work.
그러면 왜 당신
사무실을 떠나요?
Then why are you
leaving your office?
아니야 너의 사무실을 떠나는거지
Oh, I'm not.
I'm leaving yours.
이건 라일라의 바쁜 일이야
넌 태그 얼롱도 없잖아
This is Lyla's busy work, man
you didn't have to tag along.
글쎄 난 휴가를
평범한 사람처럼 보내고싶어
Well, I don't know how to vacation
like a normal person, Diggle.
작전이 머야?
What's the plan?
This spot's his
usual dead drop.
라일라가 나한테 사진을 보냈어
Lyla sent me over
this file photo.
그냥 그가 괜찮게할께
Just make sure
he's all right.
그를 잡아
내가 너를 잡을께
Got him.
I got you.
그는 우정이있어
올리버
He's a friendly,
Oliver.
쇼
Shaw.
헤이X8
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey!
들어봐 난 라일라 마이클스와 함꼐야
Listen! I'm with
Lyla Michaels.
오늘 꼬리감기원숭이 봤어?
Have you seen any
capuchins today?
그 도전 코드 내가 말해줄께
난 아르거스하고 있지않아
If that's a challenge code, I got
to tell you, I'm not with A.R.G.U.S.
난 그냥 라일라의 아기 아빠야
I'm just Lyla's
baby daddy.
지금 니가 확인을 안했잖아
그녀는 걱정스러웠던거야
Now, you didn't check in, Shaw.
She was worried,
그녀가 널찾아내라고 보냈어
so she sent me
to find you.
거짓말이면 너의 창자를
If you're lyin', you'll be picking
your intestines up
보도에 뺴놓을 꺼야
off this sidewalk.
이제 충분히 공평해
That's fair enough.
라일라가 준 보안트랜스코더를
내주머니에 넣었어
Lyla gave me a security
transcoder in my right jacket pocket.
멋지게 뛰어오르는군, 쇼
Pretty jumpy, Shaw.
더 잘뛰면 죽어
Better jumpy than dead.
알았어
무슨일이 일어나는거야?
Copy that.
What's going on?
여기선 아니야
Not here.
미안해
Sorry, I had--
누가 날 지켜보고있거든
I had eyes on me
all week,
팀 전체가 날따라다녀
a whole
follow team.
기다려 쇼, 무엇이 널
이렇게 중요하게 만든거야?
Wait, Shaw. What makes
you so important?
나한테 정보가 있어
I have hard Intel.
코르토 말테즈에서 온 누군가가
서버로 해킹을 했어
Someone from Corto Maltese
hacked into the server
그리고 사실상 아르거스를 습득했어
and acquired
the A.R.G.U.S. actual.
그들이 팔고 싶어해
They want to sell it.
내가 아르거스를 위해 일하지
않는다고 말했잖아
Did I mention I don't
work for A.R.G.U.S.?
사실상 총괄적인데이터가 암호화됐어
The actual is an encrypted
data omnibus.
그건 요원들의 정보를 입력해놓았어
It's a complete record
of agent covers,
개인적인 부분까지 적었어
personal details,
affiliated soft targets--
워워워 소프트 타게이라
내가족도 있어?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, soft targets...
As in family members?
그래 여자와 아이야
Yeah, as in women
and children.
이제 이게 왜중요
한지 알겠지?
You get why
this is so important?
안녕하세요 제이름은 로럴이에요
알콜 중독자죠
Hi, my name is Laurel,
I'm an alcoholic.
안녕하세요 로럴
All: Hi, Laurel.
일주일전...
A week ago, I...
먼 일이 일어났어요
Something happened.
어떤일은 누구나
공유할수가없어요
Something that
I can't share with anyone
몇몇은 완전한 이유가있어요
for several
complicated reasons.
전 술을 마시고 싶어한다는
것을 생각했어요
I thought that I was going
to want to drink...
하지만 그러지 않았어요
But I didn't.
유혹되지않았어요
진짜에요
Not even tempted,
really.
[Inhales and exhales]
But what I am is...
난 화가났죠
Is I'm angry.
그리고 전 그걸로
멀할지 몰랐죠
And I don't know
what to do with it
어쨋든
or--or where to put
it. I just...
저와 공유해주셔서
감사해요
Thank you for
letting me share.
타는 욕망을 느끼신
분이 있으세요?
Are there any other
burning desires?
에리카이고
알콜 중독자에요
Erica. Alcoholic.
안녕 에리카
All: Hi, Erica.
내 남친과 저에요
My boyfriend and me
다른 이야기는
전 어젯밤에 싸웠어요
got into another
fight last night.
그는 아직도
술을 마셔요 많이요
Some of you know,
he still drinks, a lot.
그리고 전 어떤걸 말했어요
And I said something.
전 그냥 제입을
닥치고 있어야 하는걸알았어요
I know I should have
just kept my mouth shut.
전그냥 그를
떠나야하는데 못하겠어요
I know I should
just leave him, but...I can't.
그냥 미팅이네요
Maybe there's a meeting
I should be
going to for that.
한달전 에리카가
나누었어요
Laurel: Once a month, Erica
gives a share like that
- 계속 심해졌어요
- 그래
and it's getting worse.
Quentin: Yeah.
남친이있었는거알아요
Do you know
the boyfriend has
반역 죄가 그를 잡았나요?
eight assault charges
against him?
그리고 그냥
스탈링시티에 없어요
And not just
in Starling.
그는 영장도없이
그를 잡아갔어요
He's got warrants
out on him
멀리 있는 코스트시티에서요
as far off
as Coast City.
And it takes everything in me
not to go after
환경미화원같이
그러나 경찰이왔어
a dirtbag like that,
but the day the cops
배지들고 이런
미팅에 오는겨
start bringing their badges
into AA meetings,
이제 여기 오는건
그만둬라
that's the day that
the drunks stop coming.
위치에 있어
I'm in position.
거래는 이밑에서
이루어 질꺼야
The sale of the actual
is going down here.
지원 안불러도 괜찮겠어?
Only two of us. You didn't want
to call for back up?
이봐
Hey.
이건 유일한 보험이야
넌 이게 필요할꺼야
That's the only insurance
policy you're going to need.
그들이 왔어
They're here.
그들이 우리 차
봐도 괜찮겠어?
You're not worried about them
seeing our ride?
어떻게 거래가 이루어
지는지 알았어?
How did you know
the buy was happening?
난 코르토 말테즈에서
정거장 용원으로 삼년째야
I've been a station agent
in Corto Maltese for three years now.
난 세번쨰 세상에
컴퓨터에 연결됀 쓰레기야
I got this third-world
garbage dump wired.
머가 잘못됐어?
What's wrong?
여긴 거래 현장이
없잖아 쇼?
There's no buy,
is there, Shaw?
[Groaning]
거짓말해서 미안해 존
Sorry for lyin' to you,
John. Well, partially lyin'.
거래는 내일 이루어 질꺼야
There is a buy going down,
just not till tomorrow.
이걸 얻어야겠어
I needed to get this first.
날 도와줘서 고마워
Thanks for helping me
decode the actual.
디글!
Oliver: Diggle!
[Thea sighs]
무겁고 더러운
걸 갔고잇네
Should have got
the heavy duty ones.
네 머리 맘에 들어
I like your hair.
너랑 내오빠랑
여행 친구야?
What are you and my brother
like travel buddies now?
아니, 우리는
그냥 네가 걱정스러웠어
No, we're just
worried about you.
[Grunting]
올리버가 네가 집으로
돌아오는거를 말했어 그래서..
Oliver said you weren't
going to come back, so...
난 추측해서 여기와서
널 납득시키려고 하는걸알았어
I figured I'd come here
and try to convince you to.
글쎄, 넌 못해
Well, you can't.
이봐 알았어
넌 상처받았어
Look, I get it, you're hurt.
내가 거짓말했어
네 얼굴앞에서 거짓말했어
I lied to you,
I lied right to your face.
하지만 내가 그때
했던 말은 알아줬으면좋겠어
But I--I need you to know
that when I said
난 스탈링과 널
떠나는 것을 원했어
I wanted to leave
Starling with you,
이건 거짓말이
아니야
that wasn't a lie.
난 너때문에
떠났다고 안헀어 로이
I didn't just leave
because of you, Roy.
내엄마가 거짓말을했어
My mother lied to me,
내 오빠도
my brother.
난 스탈링을 떠나면서 비밀도 떠났어
I had to get away from Starling City
and all the secrets.
그리고 내자신을
여기서 찾았어
And I found
myself here.
여기 외롭지 않아?
Isn't it lonely here?
난 이게좋아
That's kind of what
I like about it.
여긴 아무도없고
누구도 날알지못하고
There's no one here
who knows me
날 테아 퀸이라고 생각하지않아
or thinks of me
as Thea Queen
아니면 테아 멀린으로
or Thea Merlyn.
아무도 나한테
거짓말을하지않아 아니면
No one who lies
to me, or...
비밀로 부터
보호하지않고
tries to protect me
with secrets.
내가 원한건 니가
행복한거야 테아
All I ever wanted
was for you to be happy, Thea.
미안해 내가
그렇게한거
I'm sorry I got
in the way of that.
내가 너한테
상처준거 미안해
I'm sorry that I hurt you.
집에 있을때보다
행복하면..
If being here instead of home
makes you happy, then--
여기서 살아
then you should stay.
로이?
Roy?
너 괜찮아?
Are you ok?
너 살짝
피곤해보여
You look
a little tired.
그냥 잠을
많이 못자서 그래
I just haven't been
sleeping much lately.
너도 건강 챙겨
You take care.
무슨 뜻이야?
What do you mean?
너의 잘못이아니라
내 잘못이라니
It's not your fault,
it's mine.
난 이걸 다르게할줄
생각했어
I thought I could
do this differently,
하지만 못해
but I can't.
난 너를 훈련시켜야해
내가 훈련 받았던것처럼
I need to train you
as I was trained.
내 제자로 대할게
Treat you
as my student,
내 딸이 아니라
not my daughter.
[Gasping]
무슨 짓이에요?!
What are you doing?!
이한가지 방식이
성질을 만들어줄꺼야
The only way to forge steel is to
temper it with fire.
[Gasping and groaning]
나한테 떨어져
이 병든 개새끼야
Stay away from me,
you sick son of a bitch!
이제 다시 시작
할수 있겠구나
Now we can begin.
왜 일찍 전화안했어?
그랬으면 도와줬을텐데
Lyla: Why didn't you call me sooner?
I could have helped.
라일라 네가 걱정하는게
싫었어
I didn't want you
to worry, Lyla.
내가 이걸 해결할
수있다고 생각했거든
Besides, I thought
we could handle it.
글쎄 우리가
그의 이메일을 해킹했어
Well, we've hacked
his email traffic.
그의 손님이
코르토 말테즈에 있어
He's got a buyer en route
to Corto Maltese.
누구야?
Who?
테크 보이야 아직도
일하고 있어
The tech boys
are still working on that.
월러가 팀을 만들어서
그쪽으로 보낼꺼야
But Waller's dispatched
a wet team to your position.
그들은 시간안에
못올 꺼야
They're not going
to get here in time.
그들은 네 파우더 드라이를
지킬 꺼야
They might.
Keep your powder dry.
알았어
Copy that.
우리는 우리의
파우더 드라이를 지키지 않을꺼야
We're not going to
keep our powder dry.
바라지 마
Hell no.
이봐
Hey.
디지털 도마뱀이 죽었어?
Any luck raising our digital Lazarus
from the dead?
하드드라이브가
토스트 가 됐어요
The hard drive
is toast.
파워 서플라이도요
And the power
supply.
그리고 액추에이터도요
And...the actuator.
오, 내가 전산학 패턴을 찾았네
Ah, I'm sensing
a pattern.
죄송해요 잠깐만요
[Cell phone vibrates]
Sorry, one second.
여보세요?
Hello?
헤이, 펠리시티
존인데 어디야?
Hey, Felicity, this is John.
Where are you?
내가 말해도
믿지않을거에요
You wouldn't
believe me if I told you.
- 컴퓨터 근처에있어?
- 그런 거 같네요
Are you near a computer?
Kind of.
내가 코르토 말테즈에서
누군가를 찾고있어
I'm looking for somebody
in Corto Maltese.
실제로 조금 중간에..
I'm actually a little bit
in the middle of a...
그가 어딧는지
알아야 겠어
I need to know where he is.
이메일로 그에
대한 모든것을 보냈어
I've emailed you
everything I have on him.
... 미팅 중이에요
...meeting right now.
정말죄송해요
친구에요
I am so sorry.
It's a friend.
몇명의 친구죠..
Um, well,
a few friends...
정말 긴 이야기에요
Actually. You know what,
it's a long story.
그 많은 이야기에
인상이깊네
Heh. Why am I under the impression
that you have a lot of stories,
얼마나 길지?
all of which are long?
내가 나중에
오기를 바래?
You want me
to come back later?
머라고요? 미안해요
What? Sorry.
[Beep]
여보세요?
Hello?
펠리시티 난 친절이 필요해
Felicity, I need a favor.
우리이제 친절한
친구에요?
Are we favor
friends now?
- 우리 친구에요?
- 머라고?
Are we friends?
What?
아무것도 아니에요 죄송해요
Never mind, sorry.
[Telephone rings]
오 세상에 일초만요
일초만 더요 여보세요?
Oh, dear god. One second.
One more second. Hello?
전화가 끊겼네
We got cut off.
당신이 나한테
보낸 파일에 따르면
According to the file
you sent me,
이 자는 해커에요
this guy is somewhat
of a hacker.
맞쳐볼께 긴이야기지?
Let me guess--long story?
그래 이자는 내가알아보기는
아르거스 시스템을 해킹했어
Yeah, the guy I'm looking for broke
into A.R.G.U.S's system.
그리고 자국을 남겼어요
그는뛰어난 해커에요
And he left a trail.
It's faint--hacking-wise--
그러니 약간의 운이 필요하겠어요
내가 찾아낼께요
but with a little bit
of luck, I will find him,
내가 무엇을 찾아내면 이메일로 보낼께요
or his laptop. I will email
you when I have something.
오늘 조금 바쁜 날이네요
I'm having
a bit of a day.
내가 누구를 찾고있어
I need you to help me find someone
by googling his phone or something.
그의 gps를 켜요
Pinging his GPS.
나중에 전화해도 될까요?
Can I call you back?
이건 전형적인 날이네
Is this what a typical day
looks like for you?
믿든지 말든지
원래는 더심해요
Believe it or not, this is
better than most.
펠리시티가 쇼의 위치를알면
나한테 문자해주면 내가 찾아갈께
When Felicity has Shaw's location,
I want you to text me and I'll be there.
- 테아?
- 그래
Thea?
Yeah.
올리버 제생각에는
그녀는 안올꺼 같아요
Oliver, I don't
think she's going
그녀의마음을 바꾸려
했지만 그녀가 원하지않아요
to change her mind on this.
She doesn't want
난 그녀를 원망하지 않아요
to hear from anyone,
and I don't blame her.
내말은 우리둘다
그녀에게 거짓말했잖아요 많이요
I mean, we both
lied to her. A lot.
나도알아 이제
그녀에게 사실을 말해줄꺼야
I know, it's why it's time
to tell her the truth.
올리버 네가 말한 사실이..
Oliver, when you say
"the truth"...
내가 5년동안 떠나있을때
What happened
the five years I was away,
내가 돌아올줄은 몰랐어
everything we've done since
I've been back,
모든게말야
all of it.
글쎄, 넌 몇초동안
생각좀해
Well, you might want
to think about that for a second.
거짓말이 테아를
스탈링시티에서 떠나게했어
Lies are what drove Thea
away from Starling City
in the first place.
진실이 테아를
돌아오게할꺼야
The truth is the only thing
that's going to bring her back.
너도 테아한테
사실을 말할꺼야?
Except you won't be
telling her the truth, will you?
그녀한테 오빠가 이때까지
얼굴앞에서 거짓말했던것을말할거야
You'll be telling her that her brother
has been lying to her to her face,
거의 병적인 성질을
지난 2년동안 가지고 있던거를말할꺼야?
with almost
pathological sincerity
for the past two years.
그녀는 네가 다른
말을 할때까지 믿지 않을꺼야
She won't believe
another word you say.
그리고 그녀를
잃게 될꺼야 올리버 평생동안
And you will lose her,
Oliver, forever.
글쎄, 잘봐
Well, look around.
난 이미 그녀를
잃었어
I've already
lost her.
나한텐 다른
방법이 없어
I don't have
any other choice.
여자를 떄리라는
것처럼 들리네
I hear you like
to hit women.
어떤 사람이
다시 반격하는건 어떄?
How about one
who likes to hit back?
[Grunting]
네가 맞아
반격하는게 더좋지
You're right.
It's better when they hit back.
[Starts engine]
[Tires squealing]
[Sighs]
아가 괜찮니?
Baby, baby,
are you ok?
정말 죄송해요
I'm so sorry.
내가 너한테 미친걸
다행으로 여겨 진짜야
I'm too relieved to be mad at you,
I really am.
하지만 얘야
But, sweetheart...
이건 미친짓이야
This is crazy.
무슨 생각으로
What the hell
were you thinking
어떤 여자의 남친을
떄리니?
going after that
girl's boyfriend?
그냥 일에서 벗어날것
이 필요했어요
There's just something
I needed to work out.
전 세상을알아요
공평하지 않아요
I know that the world
isn't fair.
난 어디가 끔찍한..
I know that it's
a terrible place where...
사람들이 정당하게
벌을 받아야할곳이에요
where people deserve
to get punished.
하지만 그들은 안그래요
And they don't. I just...
[Sighs]
그냥 하룻 밤만요
For one night,
전 세상을
다르게 봐요
I needed the world
to be different.
그래 로럴, 로럴
Ok, Laurel,
Laurel...
너한테 무슨일이
벌어나는거니 허?
What's going on
with you, huh?
최근에 네 자신이
아니였어
You're not being
yourself lately.
그리고 이젠
주변을달려
And now you're
running around,
이자를 떄리고
머하는 짓이니?
you're tuning this guy up.
What are you doin'?!
아가야 나한테
다말해 아무거나
Baby, you can talk to me
about anything.
너도알잖아 응?
You know that,
right? You know that.
알아요
I know.
그러면 나한테 말해
Talk to me, then.
[Sighs]
로럴 넌 애로우가 아니야
Laurel, you're not
the arrow.
아니면 네 여동생이나
Or your sister.
다시는 이런짓
안한다고 약속해!
You promise me you'll never
do anything like this again, ever!
약속해요
I promise.
이건 실수였다고
생각하고있어요
It was a mistake;
I wasn't thinking.
코르토 말테즈에 지내고
싶으면 괜찮아
If you want to stay
in Corto Maltese, it's fine,
여긴 관광할거리가
많지 않아
but there's not much
here in the way of sightseeing.
이야기 좀하자
I need to talk to you.
오빠하고 그리고 베프 로이하고는
Look, between you
and your new best friend Roy,
모든걸 말할꺼 같네
I'm pretty sure you guys have
said everything.
난 아냐
I haven't.
아직이야 어쨋든
Not yet, anyway.
[Sighs]
로이가 니가남긴
메세지를 보여줫어
Roy showed me
the note you left him.
그리고 네가
다맞았어
And you were right
about everything.
너한테 거짓말을했어
비밀도 숨기고
I have lied,
I have kept secrets.
진실은
The truth is that
내가말해도..
if I tell you...
나에 다른 것을 알게될거야
All the things that you don't
know about me,
그러면 널
평생동안 잃게 되겠지
that I might
lose you forever.
난 5년을
여러가지 종류의 지옥에서 살았어
I spent five years
in the worst kind of hell,
여러가지 일이
일어났지
and there were
things that happened,
거기서 내가 했던 일...
there were things
that I did...
That if--
네가 알게 된다면
if you knew,
날 다르게 볼꺼야
you would see me
differently.
난 항상 내 오빠로
볼꺼야
No, I'll always
see you as my big brother.
내말은 거기서 무슨일이
I mean, no matter
what happened
일어났든, 오빠가 누가됬던간
to you on that island,
or who you became,
내 인생에관한 비밀을 숨겼어
it's the secrets you kept
about my own life.
내말은 나한테 거짓말을했어
I mean, you lied to me
내 아버지가 누구였는지
about who my father was.
말콤의 피가 너한테도 있찌
Malcolm may have
been your blood.
하지만 로버트가 너의 아버지야
Robert was
your father.
난 그에대한것도
거짓말했어
I lied to you
about him, too.
아빠는 우리가
생각했던 사람이 아니였어
Dad wasn't the man
we thought he was.
더 뛰어나셧지
He was better.
그리고 난 너한테도
숨겼어 왜녀하면 그냥..
And I've kept something from you
because I just...
네가 그걸 알기 바라지 않아서 그랬어
Never wanted you
to know.
아빠는 나랑 겜빗호를
탈출했어
Dad made it off
"The Gambit" with me.
나보곤 익사하셧다고 했잖아
You told me he drowned.
우리는 구명 보트에 탔어
We made it to
a life boat together.
물과 식량이 부족해져서
There wasn't enough
food and water for both of us...
자살하신거야
So he killed
himself.
그리고 너한테 말한
한가지 비밀이야
And that is one secret
that I'm telling you now
왜나하면 네가
엄마와 아빠에 대해
because I need you
to realize...
깨달았으면해
mom and dad,
그들은 희생했다는것을
they sacrificed
themselves
그래서 우리가 살아있는것을
so that
we could live.
우리가 같이 안있는다면...
But if we're not
together, then...
우리는 살아 있지 않을 꺼야
we're not even
really alive.
넌 내가족이야
You're my family.
만약에 네가 날
필요로 하지않더라도
And even if you
don't need me...
난 네가 필요해
I need you.
내가 말하는것을
고려해봐
Please just consider
what I'm saying.
그가 왔어
John: He's here.
그래서 저자가 손님이군
So's his buyer.
아미티지라고 예상했지
I was expecting
Armitage.
이 나라는 가치가 없지 미스터 아미티지
This country's soil
is not worthy of Mr. Armitage.
아이템은 있어?
Do you have the item?
돈은 어딨어?
Where's the money?
그리고 트랜스코더?
And the transcoder?
가야겠어
We better go.
이걸 어디서 얻었어요?
Where'd you get this?
우리 호텔 룸에서
Our hotel room.
누구에요?
Who are they?
아르거스 일꺼야
Could be A.R.G.U.S.
저건 아르거스가 아니야
That's not A.R.G.U.S.
가자
Suelten sus armas!
Let's go.
가!
Go!
아르거스는 우리가 여깄는걸 알아
A.R.G.U.S., they
know we're here.
Which is why I got a bunch
of renta-soldiers to secure the perimeter.
얼마나 돈을줘야 군대를 살수있지
It's amazing how cheap
you can buy an army
그나라의 군대를
for in this country.
디글!
뒤에있어!
Diggle!
Behind you!
I never said I didn't know
how to use a gun.
[All grunting]
[Both grunting]
라일라는 네 친구였어!
Lyla was your friend!
그리고 넌 그녀와
딸에 위험하게했어!
And you endangered
her and her daughter
그냥 형편 없는 돈을 위해서!
for what, for a lousy payday!
이건 내 나가는 티켓이야
Not a payday.
It's my ticket out.
- 어디로부터?
- 아르거스!
Of what?
A.R.G.U.S.!
월러가 내가 이걸
하게 했어
You don't know the things Waller's
made me do.
네가 생각하는사람이아니야
The person
she turns you into.
That still gives you no right
내 가족을 과녁의 한복판에 나뒀어!
to put a bulls-eye
on my family's back!
난 선택권이 없어
I had no choice.
너는 있어 존
But you do, John.
월러한테 내가 죽었다고해줘
Tell Waller I died.
그녀에게 내가 총에 맞았다고해줘
Tell her you put
a bullet in me.
그러지않을꺼야
If only.
생각 해봤는데요
Thea: I've been thinking.
집에가고싶어요 내오빠한테요
I want to go home.
To my brother.
그리고 그의 거짓말 그리고 비밀로?
And all his lies
and secrets?
아마도 넌 내가 생각
했던 것보다 못왔구나
Maybe you haven't come
as far as I thought.
증명해보겠어요
Let me prove it to you.
[Both grunting]
감명적이군
Impressive.
[Both grunting]
좋은 선생을 뒀죠
I had a good teacher.
[Laughs]
집으로 갈수있는 것처럼 보이는구나
Looks like
you're going home.
[Both breathing heavily]
내가이기게해줬죠?
맞죠?
You let me win,
didn't you?
곧 또 다시 볼꺼다
I'll be seeing you soon.
안전하게있어라
Safe flight.
- 고마워
- 그래
Thank you.
Yeah.
괜찮아?
You ok?
그녀가 안와
She's not coming.
유감이야 올리버
넌 할수있는걸다했어
I'm sorry, Oliver.
You did everything you could, man.
올리버...
Oliver...
마음 바꿔줘서 고마워
I'm glad you changed
your mind.
아직까지는 옆에있고싶어
Still not sure about flying
commercial, though.
Oh!
테아 괜찮아?
Thea,
are you ok?
그래 괜찮아
Yeah. I'm fine.
로럴?
Laurel?
난 애로우가 휴가를
갔는지 몰랐네
I didn't know the Arrow
took vacations.
헤이! 무슨일이야!
Hey! What happened?
난 괜찮아
I'm fine. Please.
무슨 일이야?
What happened?
난 좋게 하려고했어
I tried to do good.
하지만 안댔어
It didn't work out.
오, 로럴
Oh, Laurel.
아마도 미친 소리로
들릴거 알아
I know that
it probably sounds insane.
아마도, 하지만...
It probably is, but...
새라
Sara.
새라가 이걸 줬어
She gave me this.
내가 이걸 걸치면
And when I wear it,
it makes me want
사람들을 돕고싶어져
그녀도 그랬을거야
to help people
like she did.
만약에 그녀가 살아있다면
Like she's alive again.
알았어
I get it.
새라는 훈련을 받았어
Sara had training.
몇년씩이나..
She had years--
올리버, 나도알아
Oliver, I know.
그래서 내가 시작해야하는거야
Which is why
I need to start,
그리고 난 네도움이 필요해
and I need
your help.
[Sighs]
안돼
No.
올리버!
Oliver!
안돼!
No!
안돼
No.
난...
I...
난 네가 고려했으면 좋겠어
I want you
to consider
너의 아버지한테 일어난일이
너한테도 일어 날꺼야
what would happen
to your father
if something
happened to you.
올리버 언제나 일어날꺼야
Oliver, ever sense
it happened,
난 내안에 불꽃이있어
I have had this fire
inside of me
그떄마다 난 약이나 술로 해결했지
that I can't get rid of
with booze or pills.
난 다른 방법이 필요해!
I need another way!
그리고 다른 밤에 잘못됬다는것을
And the other night,
even though it went wrong
새라가 죽은 날밤이였어
it was the first time
since Sara died
그 불꽃을 쓸곳이 없어
where I haven't felt that fire.
미안해
하지만 난 못해
I'm sorry,
but I can't.
내가 한다해도
And even if I could,
새라가 날
용서하지않을꺼야
Sara would never
forgive me.
Yeah.
Hey.
사랑해
둘다 사랑해
Love you.
I love you both.
둘을 계속 생각했어
The two of you
were all I could think about.
난 그냥 그녀를 내려놨을 뿐이야
I'm just trying
to put her down.
괜찮아
난 그냥 계속 그녀를 볼꺼야
That's ok, I just
want to look at her for a while.
좋아
Ok.
난 사무실가야해
I have to head
into the office.
늦게와?
So late?
늦게와 아만다 월러가
물어 기억해?
I do whatever Amanda Waller
asks, remember?
괜찮아?
You ok?
그래
Yeah.
Just hurry back.
이자는머야
What's with this guy?
코스트시티에서의 폭행때문에
잡혔어요
Outstanding warrants
for assault and battery in Coast City.
익명의 신고로
스탈링으로 온걸 알아요
Got an anonymous tip
he was in Starling.
익명의 신고?
Anonymous tip, huh?
불운이군
친구
That's a bad break,
buddy.
좋아요언제부터 시작할까요?
All right.
When can I start?
퀸회사의 테크가 얼마나 많은지 알아?
Do you know how many
of QC's techs
이 데이터는 복구 불가능이라고 했지 않아요?
said this data
was unrecoverable?
오직 전부야
Only all of them.
Seems like this would be a good time
to ask for a few days off, then.
[Scoffs] You
just started.
내가 아는것은내친구가 번개에 맞고
I know. But...my friend
was struck by lightning
코마상태란거에요
and is in a coma.
글쎄, 코마상태 였었네요
Well, was.
모르겠어요 음...
I don't know. Um, it's--
긴이야기군
A long story.
나중에 봐
See ya.
네
Thanks.
거기서 잘했어
You did good
over there.
좋은 선생을 뒀죠
I had a good teacher.
A judgmental, occasionally
temperamental one, but...
Those are
the best kind.
[Chuckles]
테아가 좀 달라보이지않아?
Did Thea seem...
different to you?
그녀의 머리가
많이 짧아졌어요
Her hair's a lot shorter.
당신이 말하는 뜻이아니겠네요
But that's not what you mean.
무슨 뜻이에요?
What do you mean?
모르겠어
I don't know.
그녀가 너보고 말안했어?
She say anything?
그녀는 아마도
She may be...
누구를 코르토 말테즈에서 본거같아 아니면
seeing somebody in
Corto Maltese, or...
테아가 다른 사람과
있었던 걸수 있네요
If Thea was with anybody else,
I've got a feeling
I'd be the last one to know.
[Footsteps]
그녀는 어딧지?
Where is she?
새라는 어딧어?
Where is Sara?
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man